# Barbod Rouzbahani . Jarvis Consulting

Greetings! I am a 23-year-old developer located in Guelph, Ontario (willing to relocate!), and I love to help people using the skills I have! I have a Bachelor of Computer Science from the University of Guelph, and I am passionate about designing and developing websites. In my programming journey so far, I have learned to program in JavaScript, Python, HTML/CSS, Java, and C, and have had the privilege of learning and working with technologies like Angular, Node/Express, and Docker. In addition to these, I have React, Photoshop (for UI), and MongoDB on my goals list to become better at what I like to do! I am also interested in the design and the artistic parts of a project besides the technical part, since doing art (sketching) is one of my hobbies. This means that I could be of great help when it comes to the UI of a project!

#### **Skills**

Proficient: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Node/Express

Competent: Agile/Scrum, Java, Python, C, SQL, Linux/Bash

Familiar: TypeScript, Docker, Bootstrap, MongoDB

#### **Jarvis Projects**

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_BarbodRouzbahani

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: The purpose of this project is to gather hardware and usage information of a Linux system and store them in an RDBMS database. It is built for resource planning purposes, for the teams who wish to manage their resources for further changes to their systems. Technologies used in this project are Google Cloud, Git, bash, Docker, and PSQL.

## Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- JDBC App: The CRUD process for a database in a PSQL instance is implemented in this app. In the implementation, the database is accessed through JDBC, the CRUD process is handled by customer DAO, and the PSQL instance is stored in a Docker container.
- Grep App: Built an app which functions like the linux 'grep' command. It does a recursive search over the specified directory for any matches from any file in the directory or any of its subdirectories using the provided regex expression. This application makes use of certain fundamental Java features, including array lists, object-oriented programming, interfaces, and encapsulation. The management of the project was also done using Maven.

Angular Twitter App: Created a simple web page that has a fully functional CRUD system which resembles Twitter. It can be used to create a new tweet, read other people's tweets, edit your tweet (which is not possible even on Twitter itself!), and delete your tweet. Technologies used for implementation are HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Node/Express, KnexJS, and SQL.

## **Highlighted Projects**

**Score Keeper**: Created a web application using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, which is a score keeper that can be used to count the score in a sports competition. Its main focus is on DOM as the effects of the scoreline change depending on the results of the match. The UI of the webpage will be improved furthermore so that it looks better on the eye.

**The Great Wall Travelers Guide**: Designed the interface of a website using HTML and CSS, which was built as a guide for the travelers to the Great Wall of China. Five pages were designed, including a Home page, History page, Travel Guide page, About page, and a 404 page in case the user tried to access a page other than the first four. Further functioning may be added in the future using JavaScript to give a more alive and realistic sense.

# **Professional Experiences**

Junior Developer, Jarvis (Jul 2022-present): Working on different projects using various technologies and languages such as JS, Python, Angular, Node/Express, etc.

Packing Staff, Amazon (May 2021-Jul 2021): Worked as a member of the packaging section of the warehouse to become a better team player and help keeping up the pace of shipping items.

Customer Service and Sales Assistance, The UPS Store (May 2020-Aug 2020): Worked as a member of the customer service team to improve my communication skills and help customers with their needs, such as shipping, printing, and taking photos.

#### **Education**

University of Guelph (2019-2022), Bachelor of Computer Science, School of Computer Science

#### Miscellaneous

- Udemy Web Developer Bootcamp (2019)
- Won numerous awards as a member of the Tehran Water Polo/Swimming team
- Won the Triggerfish Water Polo tournament with the University of Guelph
- Water Polo player